Modern Times has been a hub for Minneapolis through many national events.
It's just blocks away from the sites of several high-profile incidents over the past few years,
including the deaths of George Floyd, Rene Good, and Alex Preddy.
Owner Dylan Alverson says the idea is simple.
By operating on donations and not generating sales tax,
the cafe won't be contributing to what he calls the armed occupation of the city.
Alverson says it's a reflection of the city and the country that, in his words,
is in chaos and local business must adapt.
People are hiding. People are living under trauma.
People can't afford to eat at restaurants even before this.
And it was something that I wanted to provide for anyone in the city right now,
whether their economic status or, I guess, time management.
People out patrolling blocks and helping their neighbors and all these things.
People forget to eat. I forget to eat.
Now, look at this pie over here. Look how big this is.
This is like you get this at grandma's house.
This is beautiful. I'm going to take a bite of this.
It's focaccia style.
You've got, like, a sweet tomato sauce.
I can say, are you using San Marzano tomatoes over here?
Yes.
What kind of cheese? Is this grande mozzarella or no?
This is actually a local provolone.
Oh, I love provolone. It's sharper. This is my style.
I'm going to be hanging out at this cafe.
So why did you decide to exclude federal agents from the free menu?
They're perpetrating violence on our community.
They're killing our neighbors, our customers, our friends.
I've witnessed firsthand their brutality.
I've been tear gassed several times the last week.
My wife was shot in the face with a pepper ball standing on Nicollet Avenue.
I guess I, you know, if there's anyone in this neighborhood that we hear about that's committing crimes against people or terrorizing people, I'm not going to serve them.
Regular patrons say they're inspired by the new approach, with some already leaving donations on Venmo or in person, showing solidarity with the restaurant and the community.
They are very clear about not accepting ice in this cafe, and that in itself is political.
I think it's a community effort because they're offering free food when they do not have to.
And there was no guarantee that they were going to make that money back throughout donations.
But not only are they in some way relying on their community, they put a lot of faith in their community.
Um, and they're putting in a lot of love out there.
Just the amount of love and support we've received over the last couple days has been quite amazing.
Like, I'm getting DMs from people over in, like, Paris, France that are doing, like, a pop-up for us.
Like, they're donating, like, all of their proceeds from the entire night to us, and it's like, that's, like, amazing.
For now, Postmodern Times is open daily from 9am to 3pm, hoping to make a statement about community, safety, and resistance in a town that has become the epicenter for all the protests nationally.